Objective

Intend to be a creative part of IT industry using all the knowledge & experience and to make more significant contribution to whatever organization working for and also developing new skills, abilities, and maturity - perhaps wisdom even which benefits the Organization.

Skills



Python Skills

- Python Scripts & Module Development
- Data Wrangling with Jupyter Notebook
- Working with plotly dashboard
- Django Web Framework



Java Skills:

- Core Java
- Spring, Hibernate, JMX
- Rest API Development with Spring boot



Eclipse Plugin Development:

- RAP web application
- RCP Plugin and Standalone thick Client Development

Database

- Good SQL knowledge of Oracle and Microsoft SQL Server
- Basic knowledge of HDFS, Hbase and Elastic Search

Build Management & Source Control

- Worked with project building tool like Ant, Maven
- Used Tortoise SVN and Git as source control system

Work Experience

GoldenSource India Pvt Ltd

> 2021 - 22 Director

Currently managing multiple teams to deliver following components as a part of product release.

Market Data Solution & Risk Master - Market Data is price and trade-related data for financial instruments that are reported by a trading venue such as, a stock exchange. Market data allows traders and investors to know the latest price and see historical trends for instruments such as equities, fixed-income products, derivatives, and currencies. Currently involved in development of presentation layer developed in Vaadin F/W which allow user to see the all the price validation exception in dashboard and resolve them by taking corrective action. Also enhanced chart capability using EChart Libraries.

<u>Quant Workbench</u> – Developed customized python jupyter notebook using ipywidget libraries which gives user friendly interface to extract the market data primarily from GoldenSource database using Rest API. Extracted data also has been transformed to panda data frame which is fundamental data structure for machine learning and data science. This also gives ability to configure dashboard screen for final representation of data.

<u>Tools</u> – Managing development and support lifecycle of eclipse base thick client IDE's which gives usability and simplicity to development user as well as client to install and configured GoldenSource platform.

> 2016 − 20 Project Manager

In this period managed Tools Component of the product and delivered following new tools which are thick client applications developed using core java and eclipse SWT libraries.

<u>Installation Studio</u> – Installation Studio is a standalone, light-weight, wizard-based installer used for installing GoldenSource EDM Suite and managing installations in various environments. It creates environment schemas, install database packages, and create application EARs.

<u>GSO Mapper</u> – GSO Mapper is a standalone tool that implements the transformation activity of an Extraction/Transformation/Loading (ETL) tool. It transforms formats of external files received from vendors to the formats that can be identified and processed by GoldenSource application. This includes standardization of number and date formats by transforming data to specified formats. Data transformation is achieved with pre-build function library for converting dates, numbers, and strings.

> 2011 - 16 Team Lead

Worked as Team lead in Tools Team, designed and developed a new Eclipse RAP web application called GSO Designer which is basically used to define abstract layer of all business attributes which can be accessed further by UI framework to generate the screen dynamically. this gives ability to business user to define the UI layer as per their need with zero development effort.

Designed and developed common control Library on top of eclipse SWT libraries, generally a collection of abstract classes which hide the complex technical mvc architecture so that developer can only code business logic to develop thick client application which saved lots of development and testing effort and improved the quality of product.

> 2006 − 11 Senior Software Engineer

Joined GoldenSource as a database developer and worked on Web UI Component to configure UI feature as per the Business need. These configurations were in xml base to design the UI screen which also needed some sql query development to get the data from Oracle Database.

Learned Java and Eclipse Plugin Development and moved to Tools Team to developed and maintained one of the eclipse-based IDE called Workstation Developer which helped to viewed the xml base UI configuration in graphical editor.

Bizo's Software Pvt Ltd

> 2004 − 06 Software Engineer

Joined as a SQL developer, configured ERP Application for multiple projects by integrating sql procedures and views as per the business side. Also developed reports and invoices using Crystal Report which is currently known as Business intelligence software.

Education

➤ 2000-02 Diploma in Software Engineer from Datapro Institute Mumbai

➤ 1998-01 Bachelor of Science in Physics from Mumbai University

Certification & Achievements

- Data Science Certification from Simply Learn
- ➤ Hadoop and Big Data Architecture from Simply Learn
- Received Associate of the year award in GoldenSource India Pvt Ltd. in year 2011
- Oracle Certified Associate in year 2009
- Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp Udemy

Personal Profiles

Date of Birth : 16-Jan-1981
Nationality : Indian
Married : Married

Hobbies : Music and Singing, Trekking, Travelling